<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>My Blog</title><link href="http://blog.jestinjoy.info/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.jestinjoy.info/feeds/all-en.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.jestinjoy.info/</id><updated>2015-04-28T17:28:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Debian Jessie: First Look</title><link href="http://blog.jestinjoy.info/debian-jessie-first-look.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-28T17:28:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Jestin Joy</name></author><id>tag:blog.jestinjoy.info,2015-04-28:debian-jessie-first-look.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Much awaited Debian 8.0 aka Jessie was released on April 25, 2015. It comes with 5 year promised support from Debian community (upto April/May 2020). Debian 7 &amp;quot;Wheezy&amp;quot; support ends on May 2018. Debian ships with systemd which makes systemd the process id 1 instead of init. Major updatded packages include&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux 3.16.7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GNOME 3.14&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GCC 4.9.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LibreOffice 4.3.3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iceweasel 31.6.0esr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="upgrading"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Upgrading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For upgrading, after adding jessie repos, type&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="highlighttable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;1&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;apt-get dist-upgrade
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;dist-upgrade in addition to performing the function of upgrade, also intelligently handles changing dependencies with new versions of packages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its better to do this from the command line by pressing alt-ctrl-f1 and switching to root user. When I did dist-upgrade from GUI, I couldnt unlock the lock screen during upgradation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debian Jessie sources.list can be have from &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://wiki.debian.org/SourcesList"&gt;Debian site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="free_software"></category><category term="debian"></category><category term="linux"></category></entry><entry><title>How easy it is to organize a Free Software Conference</title><link href="http://blog.jestinjoy.info/how-easy-it-is-to-organize-a-free-software-conference.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-27T17:28:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Jestin Joy</name></author><id>tag:blog.jestinjoy.info,2014-07-27:how-easy-it-is-to-organize-a-free-software-conference.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In India undergraduate academic conferences are conducted regularly by colleges/universities to show their expertise and for publicity purposes. The challenges faced by the  organization range from selecting speakers to arranging audience. Most technical conference in undergraduate streams are just programs consisting mainly of cultural and fun events.  If the task is to conduct a Free Software Academic conference then it is more challenging. It involves&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selecting speakers from Free Software Stream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convince authorities to conduct a Free Software Conference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting audience to attend the event&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using only Free Software for organizing and other purposes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First problem we faced was whether or not to involve technologies from Google and Mozilla. With Free Software Foundation strongly against Google products, especially Android;  we decided not to go for the Android Workshop, one of the most popular and easy to organize tech workshop conducted in our part of the world. With Mozilla in its earlier stage of development and its intentions not clear we have decided not to go for that also. Anyway we could solve the first three points easily, since my task was to conduct the program in its third edition. I am talking about &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://icefoss.fisat.ac.in/"&gt;ICEFOSS&lt;/a&gt; , a Free Software Conference conducted by Federal Institute of Science And Technology. Here I will be writing about the Free Softwares we used and how we tried our maximum to stick to the Free Software ideology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="brochure-poster"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Brochure, Poster…..&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First task was to create a brochure. There are lots of tools available. We had already created some using LaTeX. This time we went for Gimp. Next task was to create poster, and used Inkscape for that purpose. Inkscape being a vector graphics editor proved very helpful. Since it uses geometrical primitives, to represent images the quality remains same even though we try to enlarge it. When creating brochure using Gimp we faced the problem of quality. For invitation we used LaTeX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="web-site"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Web Site&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major criticism we face usually is of about server and site templates. This time we took extra care to create the site using Free Software tools. So we went for Bootstrap,which is licensed under the Apache 2.0 license.  Also the all the images used in the site are under public domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conference-presentation"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conference Presentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We provided laptops loaded with Debian for speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="certificate"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Certificate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certificate is made using LaTeX template available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="free_software"></category><category term="conference"></category></entry><entry><title>Blogging with Pelican</title><link href="http://blog.jestinjoy.info/blogging-with-pelican.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-01-18T14:28:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Jestin Joy</name></author><id>tag:blog.jestinjoy.info,2014-01-18:blogging-with-pelican.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After a brief stop, decided to continue with blogging again with pelican.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Create an account in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pages.github.com/"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; pages. Just create the repo. Don't follow the other steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Install pelican. I have used pip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
pip install pelican
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Use the pelican-quickstart command to insert default settings. This will ask for some questions. Answer them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Edit the contents of pelicanconf.py to add some more contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Use the make file to push the contents to Github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
make github
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</summary><category term="pelican"></category><category term="blog"></category></entry></feed>