<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Think Geek - AT</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/at.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2018-07-06T10:28:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Assistive Technology definitions</title><link href="/assistive-technology-definitions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-06T10:28:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-07-06T10:28:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Jestin Joy</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-07-06:/assistive-technology-definitions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;AT definitions&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Assistive Technology Industry Association (ATIA) defines Assistive Technology (AT) as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Assistive technology (AT) is any item, piece of equipment, software program, or product system that is used to increase, maintain, or improve the functional capabilities of persons with disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World Health Organization (WHO) defines it as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Assistive technology is an umbrella term covering the systems and services related to the delivery of assistive products and services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHO says that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More than 1 billion people need 1 or more assistive products&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More than 2 billion people will need at least 1 assistive product by 2030&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Today, only 1 in 10 people in need have access to assistive products&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assistive Technology Act of 1998 states it as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Assistive technology means technology designed to be utilized in an assistive technology device or assistive technology service. The term &amp;quot;assistive technology device&amp;quot; means any item, piece of equipment, or product system, whether acquired commercially, modified, or customized, that is used to increase, maintain, or improve functional capabilities of individuals with disabilities. The term &amp;quot;assistive technology service&amp;quot; means any service that directly assists an individual with a disability in the selection, acquisition, or use of an assistive technology device.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="AT"></category><category term="Assistive Technology"></category></entry></feed>